Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964
SWF007
Collected by the University of Arizona Folklore Committee and the University of Arizona Southwest Folklore Center.
Sound discs of commercial and non-commercial recordings of oral history interviews and examples of local, national, and international folk music, collected by the Center before 1980. The collection includes recordings made in 33-1/3, 45 and 78 rpm formats.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
Researchers must use cassette tape copies of all sound discs or tape reels when they are available. An item level listing of all sound discs in the collection is available in the University of Arizona Library Special Collections. Tape reel duplicates of the sound discs are numbered to correspond to the call numbers of the sound discs themselves.
Historical Note
Members of the University of Arizona Folklore Committee began collecting sound recordings in the 1940s which documented folklore traditions in the Southwestern United States and Mexico. Committee members most active in recording were Vicente S. Acosta (1918-1983), Frances Gillmor (1903-1993), and Byrd Howell Granger (1912-1991).
Vicente S. Acosta was a longtime member of the University's Folklore Committee and contributor to the committee’s archive of Southwest folklore materials. His 1951 master's thesis, Some Surviving Elements of Spanish Folklore in Arizona, is considered a definitive work on the subject. A Spanish teacher at Rincon High School in Tucson, Arizona, Acosta continued to collect folklore materials throughout his career.
Frances Gillmor, an English professor at the University of Arizona, spent much of her research time collecting traditional dance dramas of Mexico. Dr. Gillmor established the Folklore Center in 1942, and served as Chairman of the Southwest Folklore Committee from 1942-1972.
Byrd Howell Granger, a professor at the University of Arizona and Chair of the Folklore Committee, 1972-1978, is best known for her revision of Will C. Barnes' Arizona Place Names, published in 1960, and Arizona's Names: X Marks the Place published in 1983. Dr. Granger was also involved in systematically collecting documentation of Arizona folk customs and beliefs.
During the 1940s and 1950s, Acosta, Granger and Gillmor, assisted by Doris Seibold, a teacher from Patagonia, Arizona, interviewed local people and recorded various types of music and oral histories using the KUAT studios at the University of Arizona. These recordings were made on 78 rpm sound discs which were used in the teaching of folklore classes at the University. Examples of international and American folk music were collected through purchase and donation. Many of the commercial recordings in this series were produced by the Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory and Folkways Records and Service Corporation of New York City. Prison songs, labor union songs, sea songs, and Mormon pioneer songs are examples of American folk music included in this series. Noted performers include Woody Guthrie, Pete Seeger, and Leadbelly. The pre-1980 sound discs were later duplicated onto tape reels. The original sound discs and the tape reels are located in the University of Arizona Library Special Collections.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged according to accession into the collection.
Scope and Content Note
All items in this collection were acquired by the University of Arizona Folklore Committee and its successor body, the University of Arizona Southwest Folklore Center before 1980. Sound discs in this collection contain commercial and non-commercial recordings of oral history interviews and examples of local, national, and international folk music. The majority of these sound discs contain interviews and music collected in Southern Arizona by Vicente S. Acosta, Byrd Howell Granger, Frances
Gillmor, and Doris Seibold. These recordings include regional music including Mormon hymns, cowboy songs, Mexican music and corridos, Native American music, fiddle and banjo tunes. The recorded interviews concern family life and traditions, home remedies, Native American languages and Tucson slang, as well as oral histories of the participants. Sound discs acquired by the Southwest Folklore Center after 1980 are available in collection SWF 008.
72 commercial recordings were obtained through the Library of Congress Division of Music Laboratory, recorded by John and Alan Lomax. Prison songs, labor union songs, sea songs, and American folk songs from the 1930s and 1940s are included in these recordings.
63 sound discs containing international and national folk songs and music were collected commercially from the Folkway Record and Service Corporation of New York City. Published primarily in the 1950s, some recordings contain music performed by Woody Guthrie, Pete Seeger, Cisco Houston, and Leadbelly.
A listing of individual items in this collection is available at the end of this document.
Access Terms
Folk music
Corridos
Mexican Americans -- Folklore.
Mexican Americans -- Music
Indians of North America -- Folklore
Indians of North America -- Music
Folklore -- Arizona
Folklore -- Southwest, New
Folklore -- Mexico
Container List
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Armenta, Guadalupe, May 14, 1947; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... El Corrido de le Merino (recited by Guadalupe Armenta)... Interview with Guadalupe Armenta...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.1
  Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rios, Frank, March 19, 1947; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Music by Frank Rios: Azatón (El Azoton) -- Dicen por ai (Dicen por alli) -- Serenata --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.2
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Dominguez, Connie, March 31, 1947; 31, 1947; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Music by Connie Dominquez: Las Senas del Marido -- El Celoso -- La Delgadina -- El Desertor --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.3
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rayando el Solo, March 31, 1947; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.; Tucson, Az. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Rayando el solo --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.4
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rios, Frank, March 19, 1947; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Frank Rios: Adelita -- Valentino -- Soldado de Levita --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.5
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rios, Frank, March 19, 1947; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Intro(duction) -- Nosotros (Frank Rios) -- La Mileguena (Frank Rios) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.6
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ochoa, Chito and Tony Corral, 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... Corrido de Elena, la Traicionera (Chito Ochoa) -- Corrido de Rosita Elvires (Tony Corral) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.7 (in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Corral, Tony, 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... Corrido de Juan Charrasqueado (Tony Corral) -- Jamas (Tony Corral) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.8
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Corral, Tony, 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... Corrido de Valiente Quintero (Tony Corral) -- Corrido de Valiente Quintero (Tony Corral) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.9
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rios, Paco and Concepcion Guerrero, May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... Humo en los ojos (Paco Rios) -- Tiene tus ojos (Paco Rios) -- La Barca de oro (Concepcion Guerrero) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.10
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Guerrero, Lalo, Eugene Guerrero and Concepcion Guerrero, May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, Az. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... La Adelita (Lalo Guerrero) -- Corrido de los dos hermanos (Eugene Guerrero) -- El Corrido del merino (Concepcion Guerrero) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.11
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Copeland, George and Larry Cage, February 15, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded at the Old Time Fiddlers' Contest, Tucson, Arizona, February 15, 1948, by Charles Wiley... Breakdown: Mississippi Sawyer (George Copeland) -- Breakdown: Cross-eyed Joe (George Copeland) -- Breakdown: Turkey in the straw (Larry Cage) -- Breakdown: She'll be coming round the mountain -- Waltz: Missouri waltz (Larry Cage) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.14
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hamby, Wild Horse Shorty and Roy Mack, February 15, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded at the Old Time Fiddlers' Contest, Tucson, AZ., February 15, 1948, by Charles Wiley... Breakdown: Sweet Avalina (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby and Mrs. Hamby, guitar) -- Sweet Avalina (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby, Mrs. Hamby) -- Breakdown: Hey, hey, hey or Ragtime Annie (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby) -- Breakdown: Eighth of January (Roy Mack) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.15
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mack, Roy, February 15, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Charles Wiley at the Old-Time Fiddlers' Contest... Crazy waltz -- Breakdown: Waggoner -- Soldiers' joy -- Wednesday night waltz -; SWF PRE1980.1/D.16
  Original Collector: Charles Wiley
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Scott, Pugs and Bill Bradley, February 15, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Charles Wiley at Old Time Fiddlers' Contest... Ragtime Annie (Pugs Scott) -- Bill Bradley: Soldiers' joy -- Kelly waltz -- Lop-eared mule --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.17
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hamby, Wild Horse Shorty and Roy Mack, February 15, 1948; 1 sound disc analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson AZ. Recorded by Charles Wiley at the Old Time Fiddlers' Contest... Arkansas Traveller (sic) (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby) -- Arkansas Traveller (sic) (Roy Mack) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.18
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hamby, Wild Horse Shorty, Larry Gates and Pugs Scott, February 15, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm; Whoa, mule, whoa! (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby, accompanied by his wife on guitar) -- Redwing, (Larry Gates) -- Golden slippers (Pugs Scott) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.19
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A., May 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78rpm, 12 in.; Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor for the University of Arizona Folklore Archive... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: I'll be a little Mormon -- Oh Zion dear how joyful -- Come my dearest, come my fairest --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.20
  Original Collector: Frances Gillmor
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A., May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78rpm, 12 in.; Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: Twas on a cold and winter's morn -- The Drunkard's ragged wee'un --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.21
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A., May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78rpm, 12 in.; Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor for the Univeristy of Arizona Folklore Archive... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: Oh Father, dear Father, come home to me now -- Come all ye Texan Rangers and listen unto me --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.22
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A., Mrs. Verda Eyring, and Mrs. Lurline Russell, May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Recorded by Frances Gillmor for the Univeristy of Arizona Folklore Archive... Mrs. John A. Ray: My dear little son, go to sleep -- All blue eyes close in slumber -- We are here in Council Bluffs -- The Birdies' ball -- The Fox (Mrs. Verda Eyring) -- I'm going to write to Papa (Mrs. Lurline Russell) -- I'll never use tobacco (Mrs. John A. Ray) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.25
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A. and Mrs. Kathleen Palmer, May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Recorded for University of Arizona Folklore Archive by Francis Gillmor... The Crow (Mrs. John A. Ray) -- The Toad said to the bumble bee (Mrs. Kathleen Palmer) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.26
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, Abraham J. and Ethel Oldfather, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Patagonia, AZ. A Freighting from Wilcox to Globe [Ariz.](Abraham John Busby) -- In sunny Tennessee (Ethel Oldfather) -- Dixie (Abraham Oldfather) -- Froggie School (Ethel Oldfather) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.27
  Original Collector: University of Arizona Project
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, Abraham J., Don Juan Urias, and Ethel M. Oldfather, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Peter Tufts and Doris Seibold... None do preach the gospel like the Mormons (Abraham J. Busby) -- Cancion (Don Juan Urias) -- All hearts be merry (Abraham J. Busby) -- Coon, coon, coon (Ethel M. Oldfather) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.28
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Capps, Will, Jack Turner, and Ethel M. Oldfather, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Ethel M. Oldfather: Version of swapping song -- Civil War song (Year of Jubilo)... Will Capps and Jack Turner: Introduction -- Violin tune -- Violin tune -- Violin tune --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.29
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Capps, Will, Jack Turner, and Grace Murrieta, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Performers include: Will Capps; Jack Turner; Grace Murrieta... La Varsoviono -- My wild Irish Rose -- Rye waltz -- Whistling -- Corrido about two bandits, Cuevas and M. Yescas --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.30
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Murrieta, Grace, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Solos by Grace Murrieta... Corrido about Cuevas & Marcelino Yescas, part II -- Corrido de Delgadina -- Corrido de Ubaldina, part I --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.31
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Murrieta, Grace, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Solos by Grace Murrieta... Corrido de Ubaladina, part II -- Que sacrificios -- Por una mujer cusada -- Cuando salgas campor --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.32
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Don Juan and Ethel Oldfather, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Mercario Romero, parts I and II (Don Juan Urias) -- Pretty pussy willows (Ethel Oldfather) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.33
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Don Juan, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Corrido de Cananea, parts I and II --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.34
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Arias (Urias), Don Juan, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... El Aguila -- La Victima --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.35
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Don Juan, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Corridos de Fuentes, parts I and II --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.36
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hummel, Alvesa and Mercedes Amados, December 12, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Duets by Alvesa Hummel and Mercedes Amados: Valentina -- Capullito de Adeline... Solos by Alvesa Hummel: Primavera -- Una Indita --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.37 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hummel, Alvesa and Mercedes Amados, December 12, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Duets by Alvesa Hummel and Mercedes Amados: In Old Nogales -- Cuatro milpas -- Noche de ronda --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.38 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Alvesa Hummel's Orchestra, December 22, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Varsoviana -- Heel-toe polka -- Schottishe -- Mexican rumba - Juan Charresqueado --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.39 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Alvesa Hummel's Orchestra, December 22, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Alvesa Hummel's Orchestra performing for the Little Outfit's Christmas party...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.40 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Laguna Brothers, December 30, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Duets by the Laguna Brothers... Naci para Quererte -- Nada gano con Quererte; SWF PRE1980.1/D.41 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Laguna Brothers, December 30, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Las Mananitas Zapatias -- Desegando --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.42 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Laguna Brothers, December 30, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. La Gairota -- La Bola -- Soy Mexicano --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.43 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan, November 3, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Al Whitney and Doris Seibold, ... Untitled song sung by Juan Urias..; SWF PRE1980.1/D.44 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections Murrieta, Grace, 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Tucson, AZ. Corrido de los Yescas sung by Grace Murrieta, Patagonia, Arizona --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.45 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gardner, Edwin (Lucky), December 12, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Performed by Edwin "Lucky" Gardner: Bad brahma bull -- In Old Nogales --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.46 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline, December 11, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Performed by Pauline Beals: The Dying ranger -- The Yellow Rose of Texas -- The Strawberry roan --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.47 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline, December 30, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Note on label indicates recording may be poor... Performed by Pauline Beals: Napanee -- Yellow Rose of Texas -- Cowboy's home sweet home --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.48
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline, December 30, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Performed by Pauline Beals: Message from home sweet home --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.49 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline, December 11, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Performed by Pauline Beals: Napanee -- Cowboy's lament -- [Part of] Yellow Rose of Texas --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.50
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline, December 30, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Performed by Pauline Beals: Billy Venero -- Kenny Wagner's surrender --; SWF PRE1980.1/D51 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Kier, William (Scotty), December 11, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Sung by William "Scotty" Kier: An Irishman's dream of home -- The Girl I left behind -- Son of Ireland --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.52 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garcia, Tranquelino and Julio Ortega, April 18, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Played by Tranquelino Garcia and Julio Ortega (mandolin and guitar): Ofelia -- Luces blancas --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.53
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan and Tranquelino Garcia, April 18, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Sung by Don Juan Urias: Los Pajarillos escondidos -- Corrido de Pancho Villa... Sung by Tranquelino Garcia: Coplas and laugh --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.54
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan, 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Duet by Don Juan Urias and unknown: La Gusanera... Solo by Don Juan Urias: La Barca -- Instrumental: Prestame tu caballito --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.55
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan, 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Patagonia, AZ. Sung by Don Juan Urias: Cancion --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.56
  Original Collector: Doris Seibold
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Powell, Dr. Desmond, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Two dates appear on label: May 1949 and June 21, 1949... Performed by Dr. Desmond Powell: Down in yon forest -- Fiosh McHugh O'Bryne -- Old Smokey --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.57
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Powell, Dr. Desmond, May 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Performed by Dr. Desmond Powell: The Croodin Doo -- The Streets of Laredo -- The Golden willow tree -- The Eddystone light --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.58
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Bob and Barton Wright, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by A.W. Bork... Performed by Bob Thomas: John Kanoatsie -- Streets of Glencairn... Duets performed by Bob Thomas and Bart Wright: Good old mountain dew -- Will the circle be unbroken --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.59
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Bob and Barton Wright, June 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ.; SWF PRE1980.1/D.60
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Bob and Barton Wright, April 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by A.W. Bork... Boll weevil song -- Ground hog -- Sourwood peaks -- Miner's lament --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.61
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Bob and [Barton Wright], April 21, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Recorded by A.W. Bork... You gotta walk that lonesome valley -- Columbus Stockade blues -- What will you do -- John Henry --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.62
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock, June, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. The Hunter wings his bugle horn -- Green Bill -- Oh, I was born in Boston --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.63
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock, June, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. Willie Gray -- My sweet Anona from Arizona -- My grandma lived on yonder green -- Young man who wouldn't have his corn --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.64
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock, June, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. Valley of Custer -- See a weary band of pilgrims (a pioneer song) -- Interview regarding song origins --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.65
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock, June, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. O'er rugged hills -- Oh Robin, they tell me you are going away --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.66
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock, June, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. Where are you going my pretty maid -- I'll hang my harp on a willow tree -- God pity Bessie, the drunkard's child, part II --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.67
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock, June, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. As I was walking one morning in May, part I -- God pity Bessie, the drunkard's child, part I --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.68
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock, June, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. Tis of a youg sailor boy -- I should dearly love to marry --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.69
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock, June, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. As I was walking one morning in May, part II --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.70